John A. Ramey II, Ph.D.

Data Scientist, BlackLocus: Home Depot Innovation Lab Austin, Texas, USA

johnramey@gmail.com http://ramhiser.com

Personal Statement

I build intelligent systems in the form of data products that utilize data to inform human users to make better decisions and to automate processes that require extensive time, labor, and resources. My research interests are in statistical and machine learning with an emphasis on Bayesian methods.

Education

Baylor University	Waco, TX
Ph.D. Statistics	July 2012
Baylor University	Waco, TX
M.Sc. Statistics	Dec. 2009
Baylor University	Waco, TX
B.Sc. Mathematics (Minor: Computer Science)	Aug. 2008

Work Experience

BlackLocus: Home Depot Innovation Lab Data Scientist	Austin, TX October 2013 - Present
Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center Postdoctoral Research Fellow	Seattle, WA August 2012 - October 2013
Pacific Northwest National Laboratory Research Associate, National Security Internship Program	Richland, WA June 2011 - July 2012
Baylor University Graduate Teaching Assistant	Waco, TX August 2008 - May 2011
Candidate Resources, Inc. Software Engineer	Grand Prairie, TX January 2007 - November 2007

Programming Languages and Technologies

Skilled: R

Proficient: Linux, Python, SQL

Experienced: C#, C++, Elasticsearch, Java, .NET, PHP, Ruby, Spark

Software Projects (Available at http://github.com/ramhiser)